Guide to the David Low Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1915-85; Series I; 6.25; (15 boxes)
  - SUBJECT
    - Contacts outside Great Britain
      - U.S.S.R.
        - "A-E" general, 1932-42, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 443)
        - "I-W" general, 1932-47, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 444)
        - Efimov, Boris, 1942-47 (Box 9, Folder 445)
        - Kislova, Lydia
          See: The U.S.S.R. Society for Cultural Relations with Foreign Countries, Box 9, folder 449
        - Krokodil, 1942-45 (Box 9, Folder 446)
        - Maisky, Ivan, 1934-45, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 447)
        - Ryklin, G.
          See: Krokodil, Box 9, folder 446
        - Skalya, Pavel Sokolov, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 448)
        - The U.S.S.R. Society for Cultural Relations with Foreign Countries, 1941-44 (Box 9, Folder 449)
          See also: Organizations Fostering Better Relations with the U.S.S.R., Box 15, folder 609
      - United Nations
        - General correspondence, 1958-60 (Box 9, Folder 450)
          See also: Dag Hammarskjold, Box 2, folder 92
        - Smith, George Ivan
          See: United Nations, Box 9, folder 450
      - U.S.A.
        - "A" general, 1937-63, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 451)
        - "B" general, 1937-63 (Box 9, Folder 452)
        - "C" general, 1936-59 (Box 9, Folder 453)
        - "D" general, 1936-49, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 454)
        - "E" general, 1937-51 (Box 9, Folder 455)
        - "F" general, 1936-62 (Box 9, Folder 456)
        - "G" general, 1937-62 (Box 9, Folder 457)
        - "H" general, 1936-44 (Box 9, Folder 458)
        - "I" general, 1936-53 (Box 9, Folder 459)
        - "J" general, 1944 Nov 8 (Box 9, Folder 460)
        - "K" general, 1938-39 (Box 9, Folder 461)
        - "L" general, 1936-57, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 462)
        - "M" general, 1936-58 (Box 9, Folder 463)
        - "N" general, 1929-48 (Box 9, Folder 464)
        - "O" general, 1938, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 465)
        - "P" general, 1938-39 (Box 9, Folder 466)
        - "S" general, 1933-63, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 467)
        - "T" general, 1938-46 (Box 10, Folder 468)
        - "U" general, 1931-56 (Box 10, Folder 469)
        - "V" general, 1944 Nov 6 (Box 10, Folder 470)
        - "W" general, 1943-56, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 471)
        - Bliven, Bruce
          See: The New Republic, Box 10, folder 484
        - Clemens, Cyril, 1938-52, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 472)
        - Commanger, Henry Steele, 1951 Jun 20 (Box 10, Folder 473)
        - Fitzpatrick, D. R., 1937-53 (Box 10, Folder 474)
        - Gingrich, Arnold
          See: Ken, Box 10, folders 478-79
        - Henry E. Huntington Library and Art Gallery, 1937-38 (Box 10, Folder 475)
        - Hill, Draper, 1961-63 (Box 10, Folder 476)
          See also: Speeches, Box 21, folder 951
        - Hungerford, Cyrus, 1937-47 (Box 10, Folder 477)
          See also: Oversize, Box 34, folder 1183
        - Johnson, Isabel S.
          See: Henry E. Huntington Library and Art Gallery, Box 10, folder 475
        - Ken, 1938, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 478-79)
        - Kirby, Rollin, 1942-49 (Box 10, Folder 480)
        - The March of Time, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 481)
          See also: Time, Box 10, folder 491
        - Markel, Lester
          See: The New York Times, Box 10, folders 485-86
        - Murrow, Edward R., 1955 Nov 3 (Box 10, Folder 482)
        - National Cartoonists Society, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 483)
        - The New Republic, 1941-42 (Box 10, Folder 484)
        - The New York Times, 1937-63 (Box 10, Folder 485-86)
        - Pulitzer, Joseph, 1928 Dec 6 (Box 10, Folder 487)
        - The Society of Illustrators, 1945-55, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 488)
        - Swing, Raymond Gram, 1938, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 489)
        - Taylor, Laurie, 1937-62 n.d. (Box 10, Folder 490)
        - Time, 1936-48 (Box 10, Folder 491)
        - Time-Life International Limited, 1948-51 (Box 10, Folder 492)
        - Wallace, Henry A., 1947 Mar 18 (Box 10, Folder 493)
        - Young, Art, 1941-44 (Box 10, Folder 494)
      - Yugoslavia, 1943-55 (Box 10, Folder 495)
    - Exhibitions
      - Catalogues, General, 1936-85, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 496-97)
      - Correspondence, General, 1935-62, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 498)
      - Graves Art Gallery: correspondence, 1936-37 (Box 10, Folder 499)
      - Hägglöff, Gunnar
        See: Swedish National Museum, Box 10, folder 505
      - Jungmarker, Gunnar
      - London Gallery Exhibition: catalogue, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 500)
      - London Gallery Exhibition: Correspondence, 1936-37 (Box 10, Folder 501-03)
      - Nordenfalk, Carl
      - Norton, Noël E.
        See: London Gallery Exhibition, Box 10, folder 500
      - Rothenstein, John
        See: Graves Art Gallery, Box 10, folder 499
      - Swedish National Museum: catalogue, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 504)
      - Swedish National Museum: correspondence, 1960-63 (Box 10, Folder 505)
      - Miscellany, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 506)
    - Fan/Hate Mail
      - Colonel Blimp
        - Correspondence, 1936-37 (Box 10, Folder 507-08)
        - Correspondence, 1937-56 (Box 11, Folder 509-11)
        - Colonel Blimp: newspaper articles and Christmas card, 1944, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 512)
      - General
        - Correspondence, 1920-36 (Box 11, Folder 513-30)
        - Correspondence, 1937-38 (Box 12, Folder 531-46)
        - Correspondence, 1938-63 (Box 13, Folder 547-62)
      - Naming the TUC Horse
        - Correspondence, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 563-67)
        - Correspondence, 1946, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 568-96)
    - International Organizations
      - The Art-Workers' Guild, 1924-60 (Box 14, Folder 597)
      - Artists International Association, 1934-48 (Box 14, Folder 598-99)
      - Artists International Association: Bulletin, 1939-43 (Box 14, Folder 600)
        See also: Oversize, Box 34, folder 1153
      - Artists' General Benevolent Institution, 1937-63, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 601)
      - Exhibitions, 1937-59 (Box 14, Folder 602)
      - For Intellectual Liberty, 1936-38 (Box 14, Folder 603)
      - International organizations of writers, journalists, cartoonists, etc., 1936-37 (Box 14, Folder 604)
      - International organizations of writers, journalists, cartoonists, etc., 1950-59 (Box 15, Folder 605)
      - International Peace Campaign, 1937-38 (Box 15, Folder 606)
      - League of Nations Union, 1933-43 (Box 15, Folder 607)
      - National Council for Civil Liberties, 1934-48 (Box 15, Folder 608)
      - Organizations fostering better relations with the U.S.S.R., 1936-46, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 609)
      - Peace organizations, 1935-63, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 610)
      - Political and legal reform organizations, 1936-55, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 611)
      - Refugee and relief organizations, 1936-54, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 612)
      - Sino-Japanese War Relief, 1937-38 (Box 15, Folder 613)
      - Spanish Civil War Relief, 1936-38 (Box 15, Folder 614-16)
      - Spanish Civil War Relief: newsletters and newspapers, 1937 (Box 15, Folder 617)
        See also: Oversize, Box 34, folder 1154
      - United Nations Association, 1946 (Box 15, Folder 618)
      - Letters of Sympathy
        - Correspondence, 1963-64 (Box 15, Folder 619-28)
        - Hubenthae, Lare: cartoon placing David Low in the pantheon of political caricaturists, ca. 1963 (Box 15, Folder 629)
- Writings, 1916-63; Series II; 2.75; (7 boxes)
  Series II, Writings (Boxes 16-22), is divided into two subseries, Books and Shorter Works.
  - BOOKS
    See also: Oversize, Box 36, folders 1208-17
    - The Best of Low
      - Advertisements, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 630)
      - Book reviews, 1930, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 631)
    - C'est la Guerre: "Preface," typescript, carbon, 1942/3 (Box 16, Folder 632)
    - Caricatures by Low: book reviews, 1916, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 633)
    - A Cartoon History of Our Times: book reviews, 1939 (Box 16, Folder 634)
    - Europe at War: "Foreword," typescript, carbon, corrected, 1940 Nov (Box 16, Folder 635)
    - The Fearful Fifties
      - Advertisements, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 636)
      - Book reviews, 1960-61, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 637)
    - Life and Death of Colonel Blimp: film reviews (Box 16, Folder 638)
    - Lions and Lambs: book reviews, 1928-29, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 639)
    - Lloyd George and Co.: book reviews, 1921, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 640)
    - Low Again
      Preface, "Blimp Marches On"
      - Draft A, typescript, carbon, 1938 Mar (Box 16, Folder 641)
      - Draft B, typescript, 1938 Mar (Box 16, Folder 642)
      - Book reviews, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 643)
    - Low on the War: A Cartoon Commentary of the Years 1939-1941: book reviews (Box 16, Folder 644)
    - Low Visibility
      - Advertisements, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 645)
      - Book reviews, 1953 (Box 16, Folder 646)
    - Low's Autobiography
      - Advertisements, 1956, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 647)
      - Book reviews, 1956-56, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 648)
    - Low's Cartoon History: book reviews, 1953, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 649)
    - Low's Company
      - Advertisements, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 650)
      - Book reviews, 1952, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 651)
    - Low's Political Parade
      - Preface, "This World and Colonel Blimp," typescript, carbon, corrected, 1936 Mar (Box 16, Folder 652)
      - Advertisements, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 653)
      - Book reviews, 1936-37, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 654)
    - Low's Russian Sketchbook: book reviews, 1932, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 655)
    - Low's War Cartoons
      - Preface, "Garden of Gammon"
        See also: Oversize, Box 36, folder 1215
        - Draft A, typescript, 1941 May (Box 16, Folder 656)
        - Draft B, typescript, 1941 May (Box 16, Folder 657)
      - Book reviews, 1941 (Box 16, Folder 658)
    - The Madde Designer: book reviews, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 659)
    - "A Textbook of the Cartoon"
      - Draft A, typescript, ca. 1920 (Box 16, Folder 660)
      - Drft A, typescript, carbon, ca. 1920 (Box 16, Folder 661)
      - Draft B, typescript, ca. 1920 (Box 16, Folder 662)
      - Draft B, typescript, carbon, ca. 1920 (Box 16, Folder 663)
    - The World at War: "Background," typescript, corrected, 1942 Jun (Box 16, Folder 664)
    - Year of Wrath: A Cartoon History 1931-1945
      - "Blurb," typescript, carbon, 1948 (Box 16, Folder 665)
      - Advertisements, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 666)
      - Book reviews, 1946, 1949 (Box 16, Folder 667)
  - SHORTER WORKS
    - Articles
      See also: Oversize, Box 34, folders 1155-69 and Box 36, folders 1218-37
      - "All Things Considered," The Listener: printed version, 1941 Mar 6 (Box 17, Folder 668)
      - "Are John Bull and Uncle Sam Out of Date?"
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 669)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 670)
      - "Art and Propaganda," The Listener: printed version, 1940 Feb 15 (Box 17, Folder 671)
      - "The Art of Max Beerbohm," The Spectator: printed version, 1931 Feb 14 (Box 17, Folder 672)
      - "The Art of Max Beerbohm," The Spectator: typescript, carbon, 1931 Feb 14 (Box 17, Folder 673)
      - "As One Caricaturist to Another...: An Imaginary Interview between David Low and James Gillray," The Listener: printed version, 1943 Dec 2 (Box 17, Folder 674)
      - "As Others See Us"
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, 1951 Jul 26 (Box 17, Folder 675)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1951 May 8 (Box 17, Folder 676)
      - "Bereavement of Colonel Blimp," The Listener: printed version, 1936 Aug 26 (Box 17, Folder 677)
      - "Blimp Views the Postwar World," International Digest: printed version, 1944 Sep (Box 17, Folder 678)
      - "Book Review of Australian Family Album ," The Economist: typescript, carbon, 1958 Oct 30 (Box 17, Folder 679)
      - "Bright Prospects," New York Times
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, 1950 (Box 17, Folder 680)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1950 Oct (Box 17, Folder 681)
        - Draft C, typescript and carbons, 1950 Oct (Box 17, Folder 682)
        - Draft fragments, typescript, corrected, 1950 (Box 17, Folder 683)
      - "British and American Humour," New York Times & You
        - Draft A, typescript and carbon, 1951 Jan (Box 17, Folder 684)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, 1951 Jan (Box 17, Folder 685)
        - Draft C, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1951 Jan (Box 17, Folder 686)
      - "The British and the Bomb," New York Times
        - Draft A, typescript, carbon, 1941 (Box 17, Folder 687)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, 1941 (Box 17, Folder 688)
      - "British Cartoonists, Caricaturists and Comic Artists"
        - Typescript, carbon, 1942 (Box 17, Folder 689)
        - Typescript, corrected, 1942 (Box 17, Folder 690)
      - "Caricature as a Social Force," The Listener
        - Typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 691)
        - Printed version, 1933 Aug 30 (Box 17, Folder 692)
      - "Caricaturing the World," The Spectator [book review of Pages Glorieuses by Derso and Kelen]: printed version, 1932 Jul 30 (Box 17, Folder 693)
      - "The Caricaturist's Corner," The Nation and Athenaeum
        - Draft A, typescript, carbon, 1928 Jul 18 (Box 17, Folder 694)
        - Draft B, typescript and carbon, 1928 Jul 18 (Box 17, Folder 695)
        - Printed version, 1928 Jul 28 (Box 17, Folder 696)
      - "Cartoon, Political," Encyclopedia Americana
        - Draft A, typescript and carbon, 1951 Mar (Box 17, Folder 697)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, 1951 Mar (Box 17, Folder 698)
      - "The Cartoonist": printed version, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 699)
      - "Cartoonist Low Gives Lowdown about Himself," Chicago Sun: printed version, 1946 Aug 25 (Box 17, Folder 700)
      - "The Cartoonist's Job in War," The Listener: printed version, 1939 Nov 2 (Box 17, Folder 701)
      - "Cartoonists in Russia": typescript, 1932 (Box 17, Folder 702)
      - "The Changing Face of Humour," The Listener: printed version, 1938 Dec 8 (Box 17, Folder 703)
      - "Clues to an Understanding of Britain," New York Times: typescript, carbon, correctd, 1949 Aug 28 (Box 17, Folder 704)
      - "Cult of Personality: The Outlook for Cartoonists," New York Times
        - Draft A, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1956 Dec 2 (Box 17, Folder 705)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, 1956 Dec 2 (Box 17, Folder 706)
      - "David Low on American Cartoonists," Goulburn Evening Penny Post: printed version, 1957 Mar 9 (Box 17, Folder 707)
      - "Democracy Marches," The Listener: printed version, 1941 Jan 16 (Box 17, Folder 708)
      - "Derso and Kelen," The Spectator: typescript, carbon, 1932 Jul 30 (Box 17, Folder 709)
      - "Does Art Need Interpretation?"
        - Draft A, typescript, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 710)
        - Draft B, typescript and carbon (Box 17, Folder 711)
      - "Does Blimp Exist?"
        - Draft A, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 712)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 713)
        - Draft C, typescript, carbon, 1939 Feb 19 (Box 17, Folder 714)
      - "The Fifty Years: Changes in Humour," New York Times
        - Draft A, typescript, 1951 Apr 2 (Box 17, Folder 715)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1951 Apr 2 (Box 17, Folder 716)
      - "Fleet Street," Holiday: typescript, carbon, corrected, 1947 (Box 17, Folder 717)
      - "Hitler Tries to Gag Me," Atlantic Advocate: printed version, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 718)
      - "I Believe"
        See: "Mr. Low Takes the Stump," Box 17, folders 736-37
      - "I Name This Horse," Evening Standard: typescript, carbon, corrected, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 719)
      - "Leonardo da Disney," The New Republic
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, ca. 1942 (Box 17, Folder 720)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, ca. 1942 (Box 17, Folder 721)
        - Printed version, 1942 Jan 5 (Box 17, Folder 722)
      - "Letter to the Editor re Israel": typescript, carbon, 1950s (Box 17, Folder 723)
      - "Low at Nuremberg," Evening Standard: printed version, 1945 Dec 11 (Box 17, Folder 724)
      - "Low Looks at Hitler," New York Times: typescript, carbon, corrected, 1944 Sep 3 (Box 17, Folder 725)
      - "Low Speaks to the Americans," Evening Standard: printed version, 1945 Jul 13 (Box 17, Folder 726)
      - "Low Writes to Moscow," Evening Standard: printed version, 1942 Sep 17 (Box 17, Folder 727)
      - "Low, the Cartoonist, Writes His Own Obituary," Strand Magazine: printed version, 1942 Aug (Box 17, Folder 728)
      - "Low's Platform for Progress": printed version, 1953 Nov 20 (Box 17, Folder 729)
      - "Me and My Victims," Answers: printed version, 1931 Jan 10 (Box 17, Folder 730)
      - "Mr. Low Interviews Colonel Blimp," New York Times and New Statesman
        - Draft A, typescript, carbon, 1944 Apr (Box 17, Folder 731)
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, 1944 Apr (Box 17, Folder 732)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, 1944 Apr (Box 17, Folder 733)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, 1944 Apr (Box 17, Folder 734)
      - "Mr. Low Reports on the UNO," New York Times: typescript, carbon, 1946 Feb 10 (Box 17, Folder 735)
      - "Mr. Low Takes the Stump," included in Macmillan's Calcutta The Art of Life and New York Times
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, 1953 Oct 18 (Box 17, Folder 736)
        - Draft B, typescript (incomplete), 1953 Oct 18 (Box 17, Folder 737)
      - "My Critics," Evening Standard
        - Typescript, carbon, 1949 (Box 17, Folder 738)
        - Printed version, 1947 Mar 5 (Box 17, Folder 739)
      - "My Dear Walter"
        - Research material (letter from Walter Entwistle), 1943 Dec 20 (Box 17, Folder 740)
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, 1943 (Box 17, Folder 741)
        - Draft B, typescript, 1943 (Box 17, Folder 742)
      - "Nameless!," Evening Standard: printed version, 1946 Apr 24 (Box 17, Folder 743)
      - "New Characters for Cartoonists": galley proof, 1937 Jan 1 (Box 17, Folder 744)
      - "New Characters for Cartoonists": printed version, 1937 (Box 18, Folder 745)
      - "A New Zealander on Westminster Bridge," The Listener: printed version, 1940 Oct 24 (Box 18, Folder 746)
      - "No Mourning, by Request," The Listener: printed version, 1941 Feb 13 (Box 18, Folder 747)
      - "Obituary," The Listener, Strand Magazine, et al.
        - Draft A, typescript, 1936 Aug 26 (Box 18, Folder 748)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, 1936 Aug 26 (Box 18, Folder 749)
        - Draft C, typescript, carbon, 1936 Aug 26 (Box 18, Folder 750)
      - "The Old Masters of Caricature: Hogarth, Gillray and Daumier," The Listener
        - Typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 751)
        - Printed version, 1933 Aug 23 (Box 18, Folder 752)
      - "Old School Tie": typescript, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 753)
      - "People I Have Drawn," John O'London's Weekly: printed version, 1928 Aug 18 (Box 18, Folder 754)
      - "People I Meet," Evening Standard
        - Draft A, typescript and carbon, 1931 Jan 26 (Box 18, Folder 755)
        - Draft B, typescript, 1931 Jan 26 (Box 18, Folder 756)
      - "Personal Caricature": typescript, corrected, in 5 sections, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 757)
      - "The Purpose of Caricature," The Listener
        - Typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 758)
        - Printed version, 1933 Aug 16 (Box 18, Folder 759)
      - "Rediscovery of America," New York Times Magazine
        - Draft A, typescript, 1946 Sep 22 (Box 18, Folder 760)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, 1946 Sep 22 (Box 18, Folder 761)
      - "These Vulgar Cartoons," Evening Standard
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, 1929 Dec 20 (Box 18, Folder 762)
        - Draft B, typescript, 1929 Dec 20 (Box 18, Folder 763)
        - Draft C, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1929 Dec 20 (Box 18, Folder 764)
      - "This Is How I Was Brought Up...," Modern Woman: printed version, 1946 Nov (Box 18, Folder 765)
      - "To One of My So-called Victims," The Listener: printed version, 1932 Dec 21 (Box 18, Folder 766)
      - "Was Colonel Blimp Right?," Evening Standard
        - Typescript and carbon, 1942 Oct 14 (Box 18, Folder 767)
        - Printed version, 1942 Oct 14 (Box 18, Folder 768)
      - "Was Low Right?," Evening Standard
        - Typescript, carbon, 1943 Jan 15 (Box 18, Folder 769)
        - Printed version, 1943 Jan 15 (Box 18, Folder 770)
      - "What Has Happened to Colonel Blimp?," New York Times: typescript, corrected and carbon (Box 18, Folder 771)
      - "What I Saw in Russia," Evening Standard: typescript, carbon, 1932 Oct 3 (Box 18, Folder 772)
      - "What My Vict[ims] Think of Me": printed version, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 773)
      - "Years on My Drawing-Board," New York Times
        - Draft A, typescript and carbon, 1961 Apr 2 (Box 18, Folder 774)
        - Draft B, typescript, mimeograph, 1961 (Box 18, Folder 775)
      - Unidentified: typescript, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 776-78)
    - Contributions to Works of Others
      - "Foreword" to book by Kennaway Henderson of New Zealand: typescript, carbon (Box 18, Folder 779)
      - "Foreword" to Guardian Bedside Book: typescript, carbon, 1963 Jul 22 (Box 18, Folder 780)
      - "Introduction" to Modern Caricature
        - Draft A, typescript, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 781)
        - Draft B, typescript and carbon, 1932 (Box 18, Folder 782)
        - Galley proof, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 783)
      - "Preface" to a book of cartoons by Czech cartoonists: typescript and carbon, corrected, 1942 (Box 18, Folder 784)
      - "Preface" to a book of Russian cartoons by Efimov: typescript and carbon, 1944 (Box 18, Folder 785)
      - "Sermon" for Sermons by Artists
        - Notes, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 786)
        - Draft A, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 787)
        - Draft B, typescript and carbons, 1934 (Box 18, Folder 788)
        - Draft C, typescript, 1934 (Box 18, Folder 789)
    - Lectures, Illustrated
      - "History of Political Caricature, part I"
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, 1948 (Box 18, Folder 790)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, 1948 (Box 18, Folder 791)
      - "History of Political Caricature, part I (Teaching Notes)": printed version, 1948 (Box 18, Folder 792)
        See also: Oversize, Box 43 for accompanying filmstrips
      - "History of Political Caricature, part II (Teaching Notes)": printed version, 1948 (Box 18, Folder 793)
      - Lantern Lecture delivered at the R.I.B.A. Art Club
        Introduction
        - Draft A, typescript, 1936 Feb 24 (Box 18, Folder 794)
        - Draft B, typescript, 1936 Feb 24 (Box 18, Folder 795)
        - Draft C, also includes slide descriptions, typescript, 1936 Feb (Box 18, Folder 796)
        - Slide descriptions
          - Draft A, typescript, corrected, ca. 1936 (Box 18, Folder 797)
          - Draft B, typescript, ca. 1936 (Box 18, Folder 798)
      - Slide Lecture as delivered at Art Workers Guild: introduction and slide descriptions, typescript, 1957 Mar (Box 18, Folder 799)
        See: Oversize, Boxes 43 and 44
      - Slide Lecture, Manchester [?], (end of war): introduction and slide descriptions, typescript, ca. 1945 (Box 18, Folder 800)
    - Letters to the Editor, Published: Cartoons
      See also: Oversize, Box 37, folders 1238-39
      - "Lampshades and Soap", 1947 Feb (Box 19, Folder 801)
      - "The Morning After": part I, 1953 June 5 (Box 19, Folder 802)
        See also: Oversize, Box 37, folder 1238
      - "Shall We Feed the Germans?", ca. 1946 (Box 19, Folder 803)
    - Letters to the Editor, Published: Columns
      - "Low's Cartoons--For and Against", 1933 (Box 19, Folder 804)
      - "What Shall We Do with Low?", 1947 (Box 19, Folder 805)
    - Letters to the Editor, Published: Individuals
      - Catlin, G. C. G., 1937 Nov (Box 19, Folder 806)
      - Douglas, Alfred Lord, 1943 Mar 17 (Box 19, Folder 807)
      - Elton, Colonel, 1942 Mar (Box 19, Folder 808)
      - General, 1932-55 (Box 19, Folder 809)